Guide to the Greenwich House Photographs Collection PHOTOS.066
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Photographic Prints, 1902-1991.
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Classes-Adult (18 photographs), 1959-1985, [1940s, 1960s] (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Classes-Children (14 photographs), 1928, 1955, [1910s -1960s] (Box 8, Folder 137)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Contact Sheets-all categories (26 contact sheets, 3 contact prints), [1940s -1980s] (Box 8, Folder 138)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Exhibit Pieces-Publicity (59 photographs), 1928, 1935, 1938, [1920s-1930s] (Box 8, Folder 139)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Exhibit Pieces-Publicity (58 photographs), 1947-1983 (Box 9, Folder 140)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Exhibit Pieces-Publicity (114 photographs), [1950s-1960s] (Box 9, Folder 141)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Exhibits and Shows (indoor) (46 photographs), 1947-1990, [1930s -1980s] (Box 9, Folder 142)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Exhibits and Shows (outdoor) (36 photographs), 1956, 1959, 1965, 1982, [1920s, 1950s -1980s] (Box 9, Folder 143)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Facilities and Materials (7 photographs), [1920, 1950s-1960s] (Box 9, Folder 144)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Making a Kiln and Using It (17 photographs), 1976 (Box 9, Folder 145)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Seniors-Individuals/Class Members (6 photographs), [1940s-1960s] (Box 9, Folder 146)
  - Pottery/Ceramics Show-Spring Juried Show (7 photographs), 1970 (Box 9, Folder 147)
  - Pottery/Ceramics Show-Spring Show (9 photographs), 1970 (Box 9, Folder 148)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Staff (see also Staff) (8 photographs), 1982, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 149)
  - Publicity-"Child Celebrities" (see also Children) (3 photographs), 1943, [1940s] (Box 9, Folder 150)
  - Recreation-Game Room (26 photographs, 1 contact), 1984, [1940s-1950s] (Box 9, Folder 151)
  - Recreation-Gym (11 photographs), 1926, [1940s-1950s] (Box 9, Folder 152)
  - Recreation-Outing to Coney Island (1 photograph), 1939 (Box 9, Folder 153)
  - Red Cross Station (3 photographs), 1921, 1931, [1921] (Box 9, Folder 154)
  - Rooftop Play School (see also Nursery School/Child Care and Kindergarten) (17 photographs), 1925-1959 (Box 9, Folder 155)
  - Rooftop Play School (see also Nursery School/Child Care and Kindergarten) (109 photographs), [1920s-1960s] (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - Rooftop Play School-contact sheets (3 contact sheets, 18 contact prints), [1950s] (Box 10, Folder 157)
  - Rooftop Play School-Mounted Photographs, [1930s – 1940s] (Box 10, Folder 158)
  - Scrapbook Pages (4 photographs), 1934-1937 (Box 10, Folder 159)
  - Sculpture-Exhibit Pieces (3 photographs), 1961, [1961] (Box 10, Folder 160)
  - Seniors-Art (2 photographs), [1940s, 1970s] (Box 10, Folder 161)
  - Seniors' Club (1 photograph, 3 contact sheets), 1949, 1957, [1950s-1960s] (Box 10, Folder 162)
  - Seniors-"Day Center for Older People" (41 photographs, 2 contact sheets, 4 contact prints), [1950s, 1960s] (Box 10, Folder 163)
  - Seniors' Events-(see also Events-Greenwich House) (5 photographs, 2 contact sheets), 1966, [1950s] (Box 10, Folder 164)
  - Seniors' Events-"100th Birthday Party" (5 photographs), [1960s] (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - Seniors-Game Room (2 photographs), [1930s, 1950s] (Box 10, Folder 166)
  - Seniors-Music (2 photographs), [1950s] (Box 10, Folder 167)
  - Simkhovitch, Mary K.-Friends and Family (5 photographs), 1902, 1903, [1900s -1920s] (Box 10, Folder 168)
  - Simkhovitch, Mary K.-Portraits (25 photographs), [1900-1950] (Box 10, Folder 169)
  - Simkhovitch, Mary K.-Sculpture (5 photographs), undated (Box 10, Folder 170)
  - Simkhovitch, Mary K.-With Others (10 photographs), 1949, 1950, [1920s-1950s] (Box 10, Folder 171)
  - Social Work-Greenwich House (4 photographs), [1920s, 1940s] (Box 10, Folder 172)
  - Staff (5 photographs, 2 contact sheets), 1928, [1900s, 1920s-1940s] (Box 10, Folder 173)
  - Staff-(drawn from disassembled scrapbook "Greenwich House Workers") (8 photographs), 1928 (Box 10, Folder 174)
  - Staff-Athletic (9 photographs, 1 contact sheet), [1950s] (Box 10, Folder 175)
  - Staff-Group Shots (6 photographs), 1971, [1950, 1970s] (Box 10, Folder 176)
  - Staff-Portraits (44 photographs, 2 contact sheets), 1920s, 1936 -1974, [1920s-1970s] (Box 10, Folder 177)
  - Staff-Portraits-Antonelli, Fred (13 photographs), 1959-1973 (Box 10, Folder 178)
  - Staff-Portraits-Antonelli, Fred with family (4 photographs), [1960s] (Box 10, Folder 179)
  - Staff-Portraits-Antonelli, Fred with others (see also Awards Ceremonies and Athletics-Awards Ceremonies) (44 photographs), 1948-1974, [1950s-1960s] (Box 10, Folder 180)
  - Staff-Portraits-Powers, Maxwell (15 photographs, 13 proofs, 5 contact sheets), [1960s] (Box 10, Folder 181)
  - Staff-Portraits-Powers, Maxwell with others (36 photographs), 1960-1968, [1960s] (Box 11, Folder 182)
  - Stoneworking (3 photographs), [1920s] (Box 11, Folder 183)
  - Switchboard (3 photographs), [1960s] (Box 11, Folder 184)
  - Theater-Adult (10 photographs), 1925-1950 (Box 11, Folder 185)
  - Theater-Adult (82 photographs), 1920s-1960s (Box 11, Folder 186)
  - Theater-Adult-Auditioner's Head Shots (1 contact sheet), [1950s-1960s] (Box 11, Folder 187)
  - Theater-Adult-Rehearsal and Set and Costume (3 photographs), [1950s] (Box 11, Folder 188)
  - Theater-Children (87 photographs), [1910s-1940s] (Box 11, Folder 189)
  - Theater-Children (43 photographs), 1921-1964 (Box 11, Folder 190)
  - Theater-Children's Dance Group (20 photographs), [1930s-1940s] (Box 11, Folder 191)
  - Theater-Children-Rehearsal, Set, and Costume (36 photographs), 1928, [1920s-1940s] (Box 11, Folder 192)
  - Theater-Children-Dance Group (33 photographs), 1931-1939; [1930s-1940s] (Box 11, Folder 193)
  - Theater-Children (44 photographs), [1920s-1930s] (Box 11, Folder 194)
  - Theater-Children-Contact Sheets (26 photographs), [1930s-1940s] (Box 11, Folder 195)
  - Thrift Shop (6 photographs), 1928, 1930, 1970, [1940s] (Box 11, Folder 196)
  - Typing and Steno Class (14 photographs), 1965, [1950s] (Box 12, Folder 197)
  - Unidentified Art Exhibition (3 photographs), [1910s-1920s] (Box 12, Folder 198)
  - Woerishoffer-Memorial Plaque (3 photographs), 1928 (Box 12, Folder 199)
  - Woodworking (15 photographs), 1921, [1920s-1950s] (Box 12, Folder 200)
- Series II: Slides, 1978, undated.
  - Buildings-Greenwich House (9 slides), Events-Greenwich House-Christmas Party 1978 (6 slides), Events-Greenwich House-"Senior Citizen's Trip" (3 slides), Women Knitting (2 slides), 1978, [1971] (Box 12, Folder 201)
  - Camp Parsons (99 slides, with 203), undated (Box 12, Folder 202)
  - Camp Parsons (99 slides, with 202), undated (Box 12, Folder 203)
  - Camp Parsons (20 slides), undated (Box 12, Folder 204)
- Series III: Negatives, undated.
  - Arts and Crafts-Children, undated (Box 12, Folder 205)
  - Camp-Caravan to Camp, undated (Box 12, Folder 206)
  - Children-Nutritional Support/Feeding Programs, undated (Box 12, Folder 207)
  - Children-Rooftop Bathing, undated (Box 12, Folder 208)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Baby Carriages in front of Greenwich House, undated (Box 12, Folder 209)
  - Events-Greenwich House-"Mothers and Kids Event", undated (Box 12, Folder 210)
  - Music School-General, undated (Box 12, Folder 211)
  - Music School-Rehearsal, undated (Box 12, Folder 212)
  - Portraits-Children, undated (Box 12, Folder 213)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Adults-Individuals/Class Members, undated (Box 12, Folder 214)
  - Antique Shows, undated (Box 13, Folder 215)
  - Arts and Crafts-Children, undated (Box 13, Folder 216)
  - Athletics-Basketball-Boys, undated (Box 13, Folder 217)
  - Athletics-Boxing-Boys, undated (Box 13, Folder 218)
  - Board Members-Portraits, undated (Box 13, Folder 219)
  - Buildings-Greenwich House, undated (Box 13, Folder 220)
  - Camp-General and Camp-Departure, undated (Box 13, Folder 221)
  - Camp-Camp Parsons, undated (Box 13, Folder 222)
  - Camp-Publicity, undated (Box 13, Folder 223)
  - Children-Children's Plays, Pageants, Parades, and Puppets, undated (Box 13, Folder 224)
  - Children-Children's Street Games, undated (Box 13, Folder 225)
  - Children-Outings-Miscellaneous, undated (Box 13, Folder 226)
  - Children-Playing, undated (Box 13, Folder 227)
  - Children-With Animals, undated (Box 13, Folder 228)
  - Children's Greenhouse, undated (Box 13, Folder 229)
  - Clinic, undated (Box 13, Folder 230)
  - Dance Class-Children, undated (Box 13, Folder 231)
  - Dancing-Social Occasions, undated (Box 13, Folder 232)
  - Drawing Class-Adults, undated (Box 13, Folder 233)
  - Events-Greenwich House-"Bank Art Show", undated (Box 13, Folder 234)
  - Events -Greenwich House-Birthday Party, undated (Box 13, Folder 235)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Children's Art Show, undated (Box 13, Folder 236)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Children's Art Show-Library, undated (Box 13, Folder 237)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Christmas Party-Music School, undated (Box 13, Folder 238)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Gourmet Show, undated (Box 13, Folder 239)
  - Events-Greenwich House-Jones Street Play, undated (Box 13, Folder 240)
  - Events-Greenwich House-MacDougal Open House, undated (Box 13, Folder 241)
  - Events-Greenwich House-"Mothers and Kids Event", undated (Box 13, Folder 242)
  - Former Greenwich House Associates (and children), undated (Box 13, Folder 243)
  - Game Room, undated (Box 13, Folder 244)
  - Greenwich House Brochure, undated (Box 13, Folder 245)
  - Group Work with Children and Adults, undated (Box 13, Folder 246)
  - Gym, undated (Box 13, Folder 247)
  - Kindergarten, undated (Box 13, Folder 248)
  - Music School, undated (Box 13, Folder 249)
  - Music School-Buildings, undated (Box 13, Folder 250)
  - Music School-Classes, undated (Box 13, Folder 251)
  - Music School-Concerts, undated (Box 13, Folder 252)
  - Music School-Portraits, undated (Box 13, Folder 253)
  - New York City-Streetscapes and Vistas, undated (Box 13, Folder 254)
  - Nursery School/Child Care, undated (Box 13, Folder 255)
  - Portraits-Children-1940-1941, undated (Box 13, Folder 256)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Adult-Individuals/Class Members, undated (Box 13, Folder 257)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Classes-Adult, undated (Box 13, Folder 258)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Classes-Children, undated (Box 13, Folder 259)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Exhibit Pieces-Publicity, undated (Box 13, Folder 260)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Exhibits and Shows, undated (Box 14, Folder 261)
  - Pottery/Ceramics-Making and Kiln and Using It, undated (Box 14, Folder 262)
  - Recreation-Game Room, undated (Box 14, Folder 263)
  - Rooftop Playschool, undated (Box 14, Folder 264)
  - Sculpture, undated (Box 14, Folder 265)
  - Seniors-"Day Center for Older People", undated (Box 14, Folder 266)
  - Seniors-Events, undated (Box 14, Folder 267)
  - Seniors-Club, undated (Box 14, Folder 268)
  - Staff, undated (Box 14, Folder 269)
  - Stoneworking, undated (Box 14, Folder 270)
  - Switchboard, undated (Box 14, Folder 271)
  - Theater-Adult, undated (Box 14, Folder 272)
  - Theater-Children, undated (Box 14, Folder 273)
  - Thrift Store, undated (Box 14, Folder 274)
  - Typing, undated (Box 14, Folder 275)
  - Woodworking, undated (Box 14, Folder 276)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 14, Folder 277)
- Series IV: Oversized Photographic Prints, 1890s-1960; undated.
  - (Oversized) Arts and Crafts-Children (5 photographs), undated (Box 15, Folder 278)
  - (Oversized) Arts and Crafts-Jewelry-Making (4 photographs), undated (Box 15, Folder 279)
  - (Oversized) Athletics-Awards Ceremonies (one photograph), undated (Box 15, Folder 280)
  - (Oversized) Athletics-Basketball-Boys (one photograph), undated (Box 15, Folder 281)
  - (Oversized) Awards/Staff photographs (9 photographs), undated (Box 15, Folder 282)
  - (Oversized) Board Members-Portraits (7 photographs), undated (Box 15, Folder 283)
  - (Oversized) Brotherhood Annual Dinner/Awards (one photograph), undated (Box 15, Folder 284)
  - (Oversized) Camp-Camp Herbert Parsons (25 photographs), undated (Box 15, Folder 285)
  - (Oversized) Children-Nutritional Support/Feeding Programs (4 photographs), undated (Box 15, Folder 286)
  - (Oversized) Children-Playing in Washington Square Park/Central Park (3 photographs), undated (Box 15, Folder 287)
  - (Oversized) Children with Animals (3 photographs), undated (Box 15, Folder 288)
  - (Oversized) Children's Art Exhibit (one photograph), undated (Box 15, Folder 289)
  - (Oversized) Dance Class-Adults (5 photographs), undated (Box 16, Folder 290)
  - (Oversized) Dance Class-Children (one photograph), undated (Box 16, Folder 291)
  - (Oversized) Dancing (3 photographs), undated (Box 16, Folder 292)
  - (Oversized) Drawing Class-Adults (3 photographs), undated (Box 16, Folder 293)
  - (Oversized) Events-Greenwich House-"Mothers and Kids Event" (Oversized) (one photograph), undated (Box 16, Folder 294)
  - (Oversized) Events-Greenwich House-Annual Dinners (6 photographs), undated (Box 16, Folder 295)
  - (Oversized) Events-Greenwich House-Eleanor Roosevelt visits Greenwich House(14 photographs), undated (Box 16, Folder 296)
  - (Oversized) Group Portraits and Two-Shots—Unidentified (4 photographs), 1890s-1960 (Box 16, Folder 297)
  - (Oversized) Music School (19 photographs), undated (Box 17, Folder 298)
  - (Oversized) New York City-Streetscapes and Vistas, undated (Box 18, Folder 299)
  - (Oversized) Nursery School (?) and/or Kindergarten (?) (18 photographs), undated (Box 18, Folder 300)
  - (Oversized) Portraits-Children (4 photographs), undated (Box 18, Folder 301)
  - (Oversized) Pottery/Ceramics-Adult-Individuals/Class Members (9 photographs), undated (Box 18, Folder 302)
  - (Oversized) Pottery/Ceramics-Children-Individuals/Class Members (one photograph), undated (Box 18, Folder 303)
  - (Oversized) Pottery/Ceramics-Classes-Adult (5 photographs + 1 contact sheet), undated (Box 19, Folder 304)
  - (Oversized) Pottery/Ceramics-Classes-Children (4 photographs), undated (Box 19, Folder 305)
  - (Oversized) Pottery/Ceramics-Exhibits and Shows (outdoor) (one photograph), undated (Box 19, Folder 306)
  - (Oversized) Recreation-Game Room (3 photographs), undated (Box 19, Folder 307)
  - (Oversized) Recreation-Gym (2 photographs), undated (Box 19, Folder 308)
  - (Oversized) Rooftop Playschool (9 photographs), undated (Box 19, Folder 309)
  - (Oversized) Simkhovitch, Mary K.-Portraits (6 photographs), undated (Box 19, Folder 310)
  - (Oversized) Staff-Portraits-Powers, Maxwell (2 photographs), undated (Box 19, Folder 311)
  - (Oversized)Staff-Portraits (one photograph), undated (Box 19, Folder 312)
  - (Oversized)Theater-Adult (5 photographs + 1 contact sheet), undated (Box 19, Folder 313)
  - (Oversized) Theater-Children (10 photographs), undated (Box 19, Folder 314)